There are situations in programming where
one wants to raise specific types of errors
given a specific situation for an error, such
as for dividing by zero or when a value out
of range is entered when getting input from
someone.
For those situations, the raise keyword raises
either a type of error supported in Python
or a custom error.
Let’s look at a simple code example for
asking for input for the Fahrenheit temperature
for absolute zero, which is -459.67 degrees
Fahrenheit.
That code is in this 525-raise file.
To focus on the raise error, this code does
not run through guesses until the person guesses
correctly.
But, if the person tries to enter a positive
number in the input statement on line 1, which
converts the input to a floating decimal,
the raise statement on line 3 runs.
The raise statement raises a value error,
one of many built-in error types in Python.
Why raise an error rather than correct the
player?
If game activity is being logged, and this
app is being tested, one may be writing results
to a log, and raising errors is one way to
spot unwanted responses within an app and
then address fixes for those responses.
I will run the code and enter a positive number
on purpose.
Sure enough, the error is raised.
If I rerun the code and enter a negative result,
I get the print statement from line 5.
Again, raising errors allows a developer to
control the type of error to raise and log
the error if necessary.
It’s time for another code analysis example.
For this analysis, we will use this 525-analyze
code file.
Use this code file to answer the questions
in the Review 5.2 exercise in the project
workbook.
In the next video, we will review and discuss
the answers.